这是二零二五年普通高等学校招生
全国统一考试英语科听力部分。
该部分分为第一、第二两节。
注意回答。
听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间
将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。
现在是听力试音时间。
试音到此结束。
听力考试正式开始。
请看听力部分第一节。
第一节。
听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完每段对话后，你都有十秒。
秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话仅读一遍。
例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。
你将听到以下内容。
你将有五秒钟的时间，将正确答。
答案标在试卷上。
衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，所以你选择
项，并将其标在试卷上。
现在，你有五秒钟的时间
阅读第一小题的有关内容。
Excuse me, I just arrived on the flight from Melbourne, and my suitcase is missing.
We're very sorry, sir.
Could you put down your information in this form?
We'll do everything we can to find your suitcase.
Okay. Have you talked over your future plan with your parents, Sarah?
Well, my parents would like me to do my masters after graduation, but I'm thinking
of volunteering as a social worker for a year.
Good for you.
We really need to move, Steve.
So many cars go by every day, and no sun comes through the windows.
Yeah, this house is kind of old.
What do you have in mind?
Maybe we should have a look in the suburbs.
Do you often ski here?
No, this is my first time.
So, how do you like it so far?
The snow is brilliant.
It would be better if there were fewer people.
Now we've crossed the stone bridge.
Turn right again.
Look, here's the Arts Centre.
The Grand Theatre is two blocks away.
Nearly there. We won't be late then.
第一节到此结束。
第二节，听下面五段对话或独白，
每段。
对话或独白后有几个小题。
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间
阅读各个小题。
每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听下面一段对话。
回答第六和第七两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间
阅读这两个小题。
Miss, I'll need to see your driver's license.
Was I doing something wrong?
You're driving in a school zone around the time school lets out.
The speed limit is 15 miles an hour, and you were going 35.
But it's only 2.10 p.m.
The students aren't dismissed until 3.30.
Today is Wednesday.
Students are dismissed an hour and a half early on Wednesdays.
Oh no, you're right.
I just forgot that.
Miss, I'll need to see your driver's license.
Was I doing something wrong?
You're driving in a school zone around the time school lets out.
The speed limit is 15 miles an hour, and you were going 35.
But it's only 2.10 p.m.
The students aren't dismissed until 3.30.
Today is Wednesday.
Students are dismissed an hour and a half early on Wednesdays.
Oh no, you're right.
I just forgot that.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至第十
三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Hi, Grace. Haven't seen you for some time.
Oh, Kevin. Nice to see you.
Are you also here for dinner?
Yes. My cousin Fiona is in town, and this is her favorite steakhouse.
You met her last year, right?
Yes, at Jennifer's wedding.
Right. Look, are you here alone?
Would you like to join us?
That's very nice of you.
But I'm meeting David and some other friends for dinner.
You remember David from class two?
Of course. He was the captain of our school's basketball team.
I haven't seen him since graduation.
He worked abroad for three years and has just come back.
Well, I'll go and say a quick hello.
We definitely should get together some time and have a drink.
Hi, Grace. Haven't seen you for some time.
Kevin. Nice to see you.
Are you also here for dinner?
Yes. My cousin Fiona is in town, and this is her favorite steakhouse.
You met her last year, right?
Yes, at Jennifer's wedding.
Right. Look, are you here alone?
Would you like to join us?
That's very nice of you.
But I'm meeting David and some other friends for dinner.
You remember David from class two?
Of course. He was the captain of our school's basketball team.
I haven't seen him since graduation.
He worked abroad for three years and has just come back.
Well, I'll go and say a quick hello.
We definitely should get together some time and have a drink.
听下面一段对话，回答第十一至第十三
三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
There's nothing decent to watch these days on Nothing decent?
There's tons of stuff.
They've cut down on the number of news programs and the number of documentaries.
All have been replaced by these stupid reality shows and game shows, you know.
Well, they often make me laugh.
People want to watch that kind of thing.
It's good, you know, as long as there's a balance.
There's a bit of this, a bit of that.
Should we be giving people what they want to watch?
Or should we be, you know, trying to educate them?
Well, TV's there for entertainment.
If you want an education, you go to university or college or something, don't you?
No. I really don't think so.
There's nothing decent to watch these days on TV.
Nothing decent? There's tons of stuff.
They've cut down on the number of news programs and the number of documentaries.
All have been replaced by these stupid reality shows and game shows, you know.
Well, they often make me laugh.
People want to watch that kind of thing.
It's good, you know, as long as there's a balance.
There's a bit of this, a bit of that.
Should we be giving people what they want to watch?
Or should we be, you know, trying to educate them?
Well, TV's there for entertainment.
If you want an education, you go to university or college or something, don't you?
No. I really don't think so.
听下面一段对话，回答第十四至第十七
四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间
阅读这四个小。
题。
Welcome to Education Update.
This is Kathy.
We have Robert Hall from Mountainside High School with us today.
Hello, Mr. Hall.
Could you tell us about the service program in your school?
Okay, it goes like this.
On certain days each month, adults from the neighborhood sit in class with the
students and see what's going on in the school.
That's interesting. What else can they do?
They can also take adult courses in the evenings for both fun and serious learning.
What about the students?
What can they do in the program?
Well, they can change places with adults and go working on a farm or in a factory or
taking care of the housework.
Good. This helps them better understand the lives of their parents and know more
about their neighborhood.
Yes. Students have a chance to work in hospitals, nursing homes,
libraries and even in government offices.
So the school is not only part of the students'
but also part of the neighborhood.
That's exactly what our service program is for.
Great. Thank you, Mr.
Welcome to Education Update.
This is Kathy.
We have Robert Hall from Mountainside High School with us today.
Hello, Mr. Hall.
Could you tell us about the service program in your school?
Okay. It goes like this.
On certain days each month, adults from the neighborhood sit in class with the
students and see what's going on in the school.
That's interesting. What else can they do?
They can also take adult courses in the evenings for both fun and serious learning.
What about the students?
What can they do in the program?
Well, they can change places with adults and go working on a farm or in a factory or
taking care of the housework.
Good. This helps them better understand the lives of their parents and know more
about their neighborhood.
Yes. Students have a chance to work in hospitals, nursing homes,
libraries and even in government offices.
So the school is not only part of the students' lives, but also part of the
neighborhood. That's exactly what our service program is for.
Great. Thank you, Mr.
听下面一段独白，回答第十八至第二十
三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Good evening. Tonight I'll continue to share how we can use art to spread the word
about the changing climate.
In our day -to -day lives, climate change can be hard to see, but some places will
feel the changes sooner than others.
The city I live in is very flat and close to the water line, and rising sea levels
are already creating floods.
So I decided to do something to make it impossible to ignore.
I started an art project called Underwater Homeowners Association and painted
numbers onto thousands of large signs.
Each number showed how high someone's house was above sea level.
A one would mean that if the sea level rose one foot, the building would flood.
I gave the signs to homeowners, who put them in their yards.
Kids painted more signs and put them near their schools and along busy roads.
The project has already had a real -world effect.
The people who put the signs in their yards created a real homeowners association to
address climate change in their communities.
Good evening. Tonight I'll continue to share how we can use art to spread the word
about the changing climate.
In our day -to -day lives, climate change can be hard to see, but some places will
feel the changes sooner than others.
The city I live in is very flat and close to the water line, and rising sea levels
are already creating floods.
So I decided to do something to make it impossible to ignore.
I started an art project called Underwater Homeowners Association and painted
numbers onto thousands of large signs.
Each number showed how high someone's house was above sea level.
A one would mean that if the sea level rose one foot, the building would flood.
I gave the signs to homeowners, who put them in their yards.
Kids painted more signs and put them near their schools and along busy roads.
The project has already had a real -world effect.
The people who put the signs in their yards created a real homeowners association to
address climate change in their communities.
第二节到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案
转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
听力部分到此结束。